艾迪
Hey,Eddie.
你在这里干什么？ 没什么，只是看你睡觉
-What are you doing here? -Watching you sleep.
为什么？
Why?
那会让我觉得…平静
It makes me feel peaceful.
请继续
Please.
我睡不着了
I can't sleep now!
你想要我唱歌吗？
You want me to sing?
够了 我要你现在就给我搬出去
That's it. I want you out of the apartment now!
你在说什么，老兄？
What are you talking about?
汉尼拔莱克特（《沉默的羔羊》中的食人魔）
Hannibal Lecter?
当室友都好过你
Better roommate than you.
我认为你这话不公平 我是说你看到我一次就怕了
I don't think you're being fair! One night you see me and you get scared.
那没看到我的那些夜晚呢
What about the other nights when you don't see me?
那你昨天晚上起来喝水…
Last night you went and got some water...
…我好心躲在门后没让你看到 那是怎么回事呢？
...and I was nice enough to hide behind the door.
我根本就没发现
I didn't realize that.
你马上给我出去
Get out now!
真的要我出去？
You really want me out?
对，请你快出去
Yes,please.
那我要听到你说你要我出去
Then I want to hear you say you want me out.
我要你出去
I want you out.
不…我要听到你的嘴说
I want to hear it from your lips.
那刚才是我的哪里跟你说的？
Where'd you hear it before?
对，好吧 你知道吗？考虑如果我搬走
All right. You know what? Consider me gone.
我要搬到我兄弟的地下室去
I'll move into my brother's basement.
当他发现了，我就再找其他地方
When he finds out,I'll go find someplace else.
知道吗？ 我会在你明天下班前搬出这里
I'll be out by the time you get home from work tomorrow.
谢谢 我听到了
-Thank you. -I heard that.
六人行 第2季 第19集 艾迪不走
The One Where Eddie Won't Go
你看你
Well,look at you!
终于用时光机回到过去了
Finally got that time machine working,huh?
喜不喜欢？
You like it?
我在第八街跟一个家伙买的 我看到的时候心里在想…
This guy was selling them on 8th Avenue and I thought...
…“知道我缺什么吗？”
... "You know what I don't have?"
镜子？
A mirror?
很好，笑啊，我觉得很快活
Fine,make fun. I think it's jaunty.
对一个刚失业的人来说 你心情很好呀
For a guy who's recently lost his job,you're in a good mood.
不要紧的 又不是说我要从零开始
I'll be all right. I'm not starting from square one.
我可是“我们的日子” 里面的德瑞克雷莫瑞大夫
I was Dr. Drake Ramoray on Days of our Lives.
那一定可以算是一项储备吧
That's got to have some kind of cachet.
储备？快活？
Cachet? Jaunty?
钱德送我一卷 “每日一字”卫生纸
Chandler gave me word-of-the-day toilet paper.
我要去点咖啡了
I'm gonna get some coffee.
做吧，你知道你想的
Go on. You know you want to.
-不 -不？
-No.-No?
书看了没有啊？
So? Did you read the book?
天啊，简直不可思议
Oh,my God. It was incredible!
是不是完全说出你的心声？
Didn't it,like,totally speak to you?
什么书啊？
What book is this?
瑞秋，这本书你一定要读 书名是“掌握自己的风”
You have to read this book. It's called Be Your Own Wind Keeper.
是关于女人 需要被授予更多的权力
It's about how women need to become more empowered.
对，但是有…有风
But there's wind.
风能够让我们变成女神
And the wind can make us goddesses.
知道谁取走我们的风吗？ 男人，他们就那样拿走了
Do you know who takes our wind? Men. They just take it.
男人就…就这样拿走我们的风？
Men just take our wind?
对呀，一天到晚 因为他们是闪电使者
All the time. Because they are the lightning-bearers.
听起来蛮酷的 有点像是哈比人（《指环王》中的穴居小矮人）
That sounds kind of cool. It's like The Hobbit.
那完全不像哈比人
It is nothing like The Hobbit.
那就像在读 我有过的每一段关系
It's like reading about every relationship I've ever had.
除了理查之外
Except for Richard.
理查绝不会偷走你的风
Richard would never steal your wind.
不会，因为他很可口
Because he's yummy.
对，但是其他的都会
But all the others.
还有，他们总是吸走…
And the part about how they're always drinking...
…我们储存的内在力量
...from our pool of inner power.
但我们连尝一口都不准
But God forbid we should take a sip.
谁要吃根长条糕？
Anybody want a cruller?
这就是典型的闪电使者行为
This is a typical lightning-bearer thing.
就像是…
It's like...
…“嗨，谁要来一根 我的阴茎形状的蛋糕？”
... "Hello. Who wants one of my phallic-shaped man-cakes?"
你跟谁约会了？
Who have you been dating?
你别担心了 人有祸福的
Don't worry about it,already! Things happen.
所以我这次被炒鱿鱼 你不会生气吗？
You're not mad at me for getting fired and everything?
乔伊，看着我
Look at me.
看着我
Look at me!
我的牙齿上有口红吗？
Do I have lipstick on my teeth?
没有，我们说回我，好不好？
Can we get back to me?
听着，亲爱的 这一行到处有人被炒鱿鱼
Look,honey. People get fired left and right in this business.
我已经帮你找到了 《另一个世界》的试镜机会了
I already got you an audition for Another World.
好棒
All right!
计程车司机二号？
"Cab Driver Number 2"?
不客气
You're welcome.
可是我演过德瑞克雷莫瑞大夫
But I was Dr. Drake Ramoray!
我怎么能从神经外科医生 演到一个计程车司机？
How can I go from being a neurosurgeon to driving a cab?
嘿，我还曾经跟雷克斯哈里森（影星）搭档演过小淘气
Hey. There was a time when I played tickle-pickle with Rex Harrison.
世事无常，随遇而安吧
Things change. Roll with them.
可是这只有两句台词
But this is a two-line part!
这是在退步
It's like taking a step backwards.
我不要演这个
I'm not gonna do this.
乔伊，这句话我也劝过艾尔明泽…
I'm gonna tell you the same thing I told Al Minza...
…跟他的金字塔狗群
...and his pyramid of dogs.
有什么就做什么 不要随地乱搞
Take any job you can get,and don't make on the floor.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
改天见
I'll see you.
天啊
God!
天啊，我是说，这好…
Oh,God! I mean,it's just so....
不是吗？
Isn't it?
这就像是读我自己的生活
This is like reading about my own life!
我是说这书可以改做 “掌握自己的风，瑞秋”
This book could have been called Be Your Own Wind Keeper,Rachel!
我不认为那会卖一百万本…
It wouldn't have sold a million copies...
…但要当礼物送给你 倒蛮合适的
...but it would've made a nice gift for you.
甜心，我们得走了
Sweetie,we've got to go.
不，为什么我们做什么事 都得照你的时间表来呢？
No! Why do we always have to do everything according to your timetable?
事实上，我们照的是 电影院的时间表
Actually,it's the movie theater that has the timetable.
这样我们才不会错过开头啊
It's so you don't miss the beginning.
不，你瞧，这不是关于电影院 这是关于你偷了我的风
This isn't about the movie theater. This is about you stealing my wind.
加油，姑娘
You go,girl!
我没法收回那句话了，是不是？
I can't pull that off,can l?
对不起，你的风？
Excuse me,your wind?
对，我的风
Yes,my wind.
你不让我吹，怎么能长大？
How do you expect me to grow if you won't let me blow?
你知道…
You know I don't...
…我倒不会反对啊
... have a problem with that.
我只是很需要 自己一个人静一静
I just really need to be with myself right now.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你说得对，我不需要跟他道歉
You're right. I don't have to apologize.
抱歉，该死
Sorry. Damn it!
怎么了？ 不知道
-What is it? -I don't know.
是关于什么风呀树呀…
It's got all this stuff about wind and trees...
…里头还有什么神圣的池塘
...and some sacred pool.
我不是很懂 但她…她蛮不高兴的
I don't really get it. But she's pretty upset about it.
所以我不跟看书的女人约会
This is why I don't date women who read.
那是什么？
What's that?
我的信用卡帐单
It's my VlSA bill.
两封里的第一封
Envelope one of two.
不可能是好事 打开来看看
-That can't be good. -Open it,open it.
天啊
Oh,my God!
你看看 我怎么会花这么多钱？
Look at this! How did I spend so much money?
乔伊，那只是最低应缴金额 总金额在这里
That's just the minimum amount. That's your total.
你在“狩猎陶瓷” 花了3500块钱？
Thirty-five hundred dollars at "Porcelain Safari"?
我的动物
My animals.
那店员说很适合我 他讲话有口音，我被搞迷糊了
The guy said they suited me. He spoke with an accent. I was confused.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do!
我想你可以从 《另一个世界》开计程车开始
You can start by driving a cab on Another World.
什么？ 那个试镜？
-What? -That audition?
那只有两句台词
That's a two-line part!
乔伊，你欠“我爱树脂” 1100块钱
Joey,you owe $1100 at "I Love Lucite."
怎么样？ 所以就认命吧，老兄
-So what? -So suck it up,man.
那是工作，钱
It's a job. It's money.
听着，我不需要你跟我来批判 施舍，卖弄学问那一套东西
I don't need you getting judgmental and condescending and pedantic.
“每日一字”卫生纸里的话？
Toilet paper?
听着，我没有那样 我只是很实际而已
I'm not being any of those things. I'm being realistic.
别说了，你是我的朋友才对
You're supposed to be my friend!
我是你的朋友
I am your friend.
那你跟我说像… 像“乔伊，没问题的”
Then tell me things like,"You'll be fine."
“撑下去 你会得到大角色的，我知道”
And "Something big's gonna come along. I know it!"
但是我不知道
But I don't know it.
我只知道你欠“缤纷世界” 这家店2300大洋
What I do know is you owe $2300 at "lsn't It Chromantic?"
罗斯，我知道我欠多少
I'm aware of what I owe.
那就讲一点道理啊 你奋斗了十年才得到那份工作
Then get some sense. It took you 10 years to get that job.
谁知道下一个机会还要等多久 我不想听这个
-How long till you get another? -I don't want to hear this!
我只是说…
I'm just saying....
那就别“只是说”
Well,don't "just say"!
或许我该走了
Maybe I should just go.
好，咱们待会儿见
I'll see you later.
你考虑看看
Just think about it.
我不需要考虑
I don't need to think about it!
我演过德瑞克雷莫瑞大夫
I was Dr. Drake Ramoray!
那是大角色
That was huge!
大机会还会出现的，你等着瞧
Big things are gonna happen! You'll see!
罗斯？
Ross!
你还在那里吗？
You still there?
艾迪，你还在这里干什么？
What are you still doing here?
只是在做一些基本的脱水水果和蔬菜
Just some basic dehydrating of fruits and vegetables.
老天爷，这玩意儿太棒了
Man alive,this thing's fantastic!
听我说，艾迪 你有没有忘记什么事？
Aren't you forgetting anything?
看，我买了一条新的金鱼
Oh,yeah. I got us a new goldfish.
它比上一条活泼多了
He's feistier than the last one.
对，大概是因为上一条是培珀莉农场（知名饼干公司）做的吧
Maybe because the last one was made by Pepperidge Farm.
艾迪，你现在是不是有件事 必须要马上去做的？
Eddie,isn't there something you're supposed to be doing now?
除非是跟干燥脱水能扯上关系
Not unless it's got something to do with dehydrating.
因为现在我是脱水疯子
Because right now,I'm a dehydrating maniac!
你必须要帮我一个忙 我以为我们讲好了…
I thought we had a deal. I thought by the time I got
你知道那是什么吗？
You know what that is?
你上个室友的肾？
Your last roommate's kidney?
那是一颗蕃茄
That's a tomato.
这个一定要拿来当摆饰
This one definitely goes in the display.
甘瑟，柠檬汁带走
Hey,Gunther. Let me get a lemonade to go.
柠檬汁？
Lemonade?
你没事吧？
You okay,man?
只是事业不太顺利
It's career stuff.
不知道你听到没有 他们杀了我扮演的人物
They killed off my character on the show.
真不幸，怎么杀的？
That's too bad. How'd they do it?
我掉下了电梯井
I fell down an elevator shaft.
真逊
That sucks.
我是雪崩的时候被活埋的
I was buried in an avalanche.
什么？
What?
我以前演过《我的孩子们》的布莱
I used to be Brice on All My Children.
干嘛大家都要看我睡觉？
Why must everybody watch me sleep?
不准再看我睡觉了 我不准…
There'll be no more watching me sleep! No more...
…别再看了
...watching!
我有些好东西脱水哦 我有葡萄，还有杏桃
I got some great stuff to dehydrate. Grapes,apricots.
还有我想看这些水球脱水后 会是什么德性，一定很酷
I thought it'd be cool to see what happens with these water balloons.
出去…
Get out. Get out,get out,get out!
什么？ 你搬出去
-What? -You! Move out!
带着水果，带着你愚蠢的水果 给我搬出去
Take your fruit! Your stupid small fruit and get out!
你要我搬出去？
You want me to move out?
我得告诉你，老兄 这有点突然，你不认为吗？
I gotta tell you,that's kind of out of the blue,don't you think?
这不是突如其来
This is not out of the blue!
这是突如其来到极点了
This is smack-dab in the middle of the blue!
轻松一点，放轻松，兄弟
Relax! Take it easy,buddy!
你不用告诉我两次
You don't have to tell me twice.
会有人来拿我的东西
Someone will be by for my stuff.
不过你以为我会让我的鱼 跟你独处，那你就疯了
If you think I'm leaving you alone with my fish,you're insane!
要我帮忙吗？
You want some help?
不用
No help required,chico!
你不会每天都看到的
You don't see that every day.
一直开到机场？ 那超过了三十哩
All the way to the airport,huh? You know,that's over 30 miles.
我估计大概要好多元
That's gonna cost you about so bucks.
对不起，你说错了，是五十元
Excuse me,that's fifty bucks.
5…0…元
Five-O dollars.
你知道为什么吗？ 字模糊了因为是传真过来的
You know what it is? It's smudgy because they're fax pages.
当我在“我们的日子” 演德瑞克雷莫瑞大夫的时候…
When I was on Days of our Lives as Dr. Drake Ramoray...
…他们会送来 用纸打的整个剧本来
...they'd send over the whole script on real paper.
那太棒了
That's great.
如果你想加长这场戏 像是出了车祸之类的…
If you wanted to expand this scene,like have the cab crash...
…我可以投入进去…
... I could attend to the victims...
…因为我有医疗演出的背景
... because I have a background in medical acting.
听我说，谢谢你来
Okay,listen,thanks for coming in.
不…别谢谢我来 至少让我演完
Don't thank me for coming in. At least let me finish.
我们可以走高速公路…
We could take the expressway...
但这种时候我们还是走“羔羊皮”（与“桥”形似）比较好一点
... but this time of day you're better off taking the budge.
你们的意思是“桥” 对不对？
You were going for bridge there,weren't you?
我今天会很愉快
I'll have a good day.
亲爱的，我知道你不是这个意思 我知道，我也是
Honey, I know you didn't mean to.I know, me too.
瑞秋，等等，你应该过来做测试
Hang up. You're supposed to be taking a goddess quiz.
中途给你男朋友打电话,你应该扣100分
You should lose 1 00 points for calling your boyfriend in the middle of it.
第28个问题
Question number 28.
“你有没有让闪电使者 取走过你的风？”
"Have you ever allowed a lightning-bearer to take your wind?"
我必须说，没有
I would have to say no.
而我必须说…
And I would have to say....
什么？
What?
你不记得那个演木偶戏的吗？
Do you not remember the puppet guy?
对，你完全让他在你内在力量的池子里洗脚
You totally let him wash his feet in the pool of your inner power.
还有他的木偶
And his puppet too!
对 但至少不在我第一次约会…
Well,at least I didn't let some guy...
…就让人家进入 我的正义真理的森林里啊
...into the forest of my righteous truth on the first date!
谁啊？ 保罗
-Who? -Paul!
继续，继续下一个
Moving on,moving on. Next question.
好，第29题
Okay,number 29.
你曾经为一个闪电使者…
"Have you ever betrayed another goddess...
…背叛过另一位女神吗？ 第30题
...for a lightning-bearer?" Okay,number 30.
回到第29题！
Whoa,whoa,whoa! Let's go back to 29.
…就我记得的没有
Not to my recollection.
好吧，丹尼阿什克，九年级
Danny Arshack,ninth grade.
瑞秋 你知道那瓶子完全指向我的（转瓶子接吻的游戏）
You know the bottle was pointing at me.
那是因为你的体积太庞大了
Only because you took up half the circle!
听你们两个说的 真是悲哀
Listen to you two. It's so sad.
这下子看来我真该一个人 去参加女神会议了
Looks like I'll be going to the goddess meetings alone.
等他们发现杰森贺利跟莫妮卡才分手了一个小时…
Not when they find out you slept with Jason Hurley...
…你就跟他上床了呢？
...an hour after he broke up with Monica.
一小时？
One hour?
你可真会挑拨离间
You are such a leaf blower!
-池塘下水道 -折弯的树枝 -猴子屁股
-Pool-drainer.-Twig-snapper.Monkey butt.-Monkey butt.
-这不是书里的话 -不是
-That isn't in the book.-No.
但你就是这样的
But that's what you are.
小心那个三维立体的最后的晚餐 犹大有点松了
Be careful with that 3-D Last Supper. Judas is a little loose.
这怎么回事？
Oh,my God! What's going on?
他们拿走了我的东西 我想你说得对
They're taking all my stuff back. I guess you were right.
不，听着，我说得不对 我就是来告诉你这个的
No,I wasn't right. That's what I came here to tell you.
因为那天我的心 完全在我自己的事情上头
I was totally hung up on my own stuff the other day.
你听我说嘛，需要安全感的人是我
No,listen. I need the whole security thing,you know?
我需要完全掌握 下次薪水从哪儿来，但你不
To know where my next paycheck is coming from. But you don't need that.
我觉得你真了得
And that's amazing to me.
我永远都无法像你，乔伊
I could never do what you do.
谢了，罗斯 对，而且你应该等待更大的
-Thanks. -You hold out for something bigger.
你不知道我多么敬重…
I can't tell you how much respect I have...
…你不去那个 计程车司机的试镜
...for you not going to that stupid audition.
我去了 太棒了，结果呢？
-I went. -Great! How did it go?
我没得到 真有你的
-I didn't get it. -Good for you!
你在实现梦想
You're living the dream!
好吧
All right,then!
别带走鹦鹉
Not my parrot.
我看不下去了
I can't watch this.
等等…
Hey,hold on,hold on.
这要多少… 救那只鸟要多少钱？
How much for the.... How much to save the bird?
1200.-美金？
-Twelve hundred. -Dollars?
你花1200美金买只塑料鸟
You spent $1200 on a plastic bird?
那是一时冲动 它在收银机附近
It was an impulse buy. Near the register.
去吧，把鸟带走吧
Go ahead with the bird.
你有没有大约两百左右的？
Do you have anything for around $200?
那只狗
The dog.
我买了
I'll take it.
送给你，老兄
My gift to you,man.
谢了，罗斯
Thanks,Ross!
我真的很喜欢那只鸟
I really liked that bird,though.
不过这只狗…
But the dog!
你们的蛋糕
Here are your cakes.
我们没点蛋糕
We didn't order cake.
我知道，是我请的
No,I know. They're from me.
听着，两位，这样不好
You guys,this is not good.
我是说被男人偷走我们的风 就够惨了…
We have enough trouble with guys stealing our wind...
…何苦再自相残杀呢？
...without taking it from each other.
你说得对
You're right.
我爱你们，女神们
I love you goddesses.
我再也不会吸走你们的风了
I don't ever want to suck your wind again.
谢谢，我们和好了？ 和好了
-Thank you. So are we good? -We're good.
和好了？
We're good?
好，我那把蛋糕送回去 因为他们会从我薪水里扣
Let me take these back. They'll take it out of my paycheck.
叮咚，那个疯子走了
Ding-dong,the psycho's gone!
这次你确定？
Are you sure this time?
对…我亲眼看到他离开的
I actually saw him leave.
那家伙拿着一个人头在窗口
That guy is holding a human head.
他拿着一个人头
He's holding a human head!
你瞧，老兄
Check it out,man!
我在梅西百货后面巷子的 模特儿上头摘下来的
I tore it off a mannequin in the alley behind Macy's.
梅西后面没有巷子
There's no alley behind Macy's.
所以我是在少女部摘的 有什么差别呢？
So I got it in the junior miss department. Big diff.
你瞧瞧，老兄，这样我们下次 鸡尾酒会就有得聊了
It'll make a hell of a conversation piece at our next cocktail party.
“下次的鸡尾酒会”？
"Our next cocktail party"?
对呀，可以拿来放洋芋片 弄成一个洋芋片小妞儿
We'll put chips in it. We'll make it a chip chick.
你记得昨天发生的事吗？
Do you remember yesterday?
我想我模模糊糊的记得
Yes,I think I vaguely recall it.
那么你还记得 昨天你跟我说的话吗？
Do you remember talking to me yesterday?
发生了什么事？
So what happened?
我们跑去拉斯维加斯，老兄
We took a road trip to Las Vegas!
我的天啊
Oh,sweet Moses!
那么这次的旅行 你们有没有赢钱呢？
So on this road trip,did you win any money?
没有，我输光了 但这位21点先生赢了
I crapped out. But Mr. 21 here! He cleans up!
300块，他买这双新鞋给我
$300! He buys me these new shoes.
很棒吧？
Nice.
咱们楼上见了，再见
See you upstairs. See you,pals!
还有别人开始很喜欢他吗？
Is anyone else starting to really like him?
需要我效劳吗？
May I help you?
我的钥匙为什么不能用了？ 我的东西为什么都在楼下？
Why doesn't my key work,and what's my stuff doing downstairs?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们有见过吗？
Have we met?
我是艾迪，呆子，你的室友
It's Eddie,you freak! Your roommate.
对不起…
I'm sorry...
…我有室友的
... I already have a roommate.
他住很多年了 我不知道你在说什么，老兄
He's lived here for years. I don't know what you're talking about.
他搬出去以后我才搬进来的
No,he moved out and I moved in.
如果是那样的话 我们应该记得才对
Well,I think we'd remember something like that.
我知道我会
I know I would.
说得有道理
That's a good point.
好
Okay,wow.
那我想我记错房子了
I guess I got the wrong apartment.
两位，对不起，对不起 没关系
-I'm terribly sorry. -Hey,no problem.
再见了
See you.
再会了，干燥水果的疯子
Goodbye,you fruit-drying psychopath.
乔伊，要我帮你打开行李吗？ 不用了
-You want me to help you unpack? -Nah,I'm okay.
我只是想让你知道 我是不得已才搬回来的
Just so you know,I'm not moving back in because I have to.
是不得已没错…
I mean,I do have to,but....
但是在那个地方 并不是真的…
It's just that that place,it wasn't really....
我是说，这里…
I mean,this is....
欢迎回家，老兄
Welcome home,man.
小试一下身手？ 没问题
-A little foos? -Absolutely!
这颗球怎么了？
What happened to the foosball?
那是颗哈蜜瓜
It's a cantaloupe.
乔伊，每次罗斯来 我们都要把这玩意拖出来吗？
Are we gonna bring this out every time Ross comes over?
他付了很多钱买这个
He paid a lot of money for it.
我要用不同的方式来抱它
I'm gonna hold him a different way.
你真的那么讨厌这个 那当初为何要买它呢？
If you hated it so much,why'd you buy it in the first place?
我那边有一整个陶瓷动物园嘛
Well,I had a whole ceramic zoo thing going over there.
现在少了其他动物 看起来就很俗了
But without the other ones,it looks tacky.
是的，跟这个东西一比，其他的都很不错
Yeah. With things like this,more is always better.
它会控制大小便吗？ 还是会到处留下小瓷器便便？
Is he housetrained or will he leave little bathroom tiles all over?
别动
Stay.
Stay!
好假狗
Good fake dog.